Guide to the Naval History Society Collection 1721-1995 (bulk 1781-1936) MS 439
New-York Historical Society
- Series 16. John Ericsson (1831-1893; bulk 1862-1888)
  - Correspondence, 1873 August-September (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1873 October - November (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1873 December (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1874 January - March (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1874 April (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1874 May-June (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1874 July (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1874 August (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1874 September (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1874 October 1-14 (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1874 October 15-28 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1874 November - December (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1875 January - March (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1875 April - July (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1875 August - December (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1876 January (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1876 February (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1876 March (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1876 April - May (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1876 June (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1876 July - August (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1876 September - October (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1876 November - December (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1877 January - February (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, 1877 March - April (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, 1877 May (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1877 June (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Correspondence, 1877 July (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1877 August - September (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1877 October (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1877 November - December (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1878 January - February (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1878 March (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1878 April (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1878 May (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1878 June - July (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1878 August (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1878 September (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1878 October (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1878 November (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1878 December (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1879 January (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1879 February - March (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1879 April (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1879 May (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1879 June (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1879 July (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1879 August (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1879 September - October (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1879 November (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1879 December (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1880 January - March (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1880 April (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1880 May-June (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1880 July (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1880 August (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1880 September - October (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1880 November (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1880 December (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1881 January (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1881 February (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1881 March - April (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1881 May - June (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1881 July - September (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1881 October - December (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1882 January (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1882 February (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1882 March - April (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1882 May - June (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1882 July - September (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1882 October (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1882 November (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1883 January (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1883 February (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1883 March (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1883 April (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1883 May (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1883 June (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1883 July (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1883 August (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1883 September (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1883 October (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1883 November (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1883 December (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, Undated [1883] (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1884 January (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1884 February (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1884 March - April (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1884 May - June (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1884 July - August (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1884 September - October (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1884 November - December (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1885 January (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1885 February (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1885 March - April (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1885 May - July (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1885 August (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1885 September (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1885 October (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1885 November (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1885 December (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1886 January - February (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1886 March - April (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1886 May - June (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1886 July (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1886 August (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Essays: Diathermancy of the terrestrial atmosphere; Zenith distances at equal time before and after noon, 1886 August - September (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1886 September - October (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1886 November - December (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1887 January (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1887 February (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1887 March (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1887 April (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1887 May - June (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, 1887 July (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1887 August (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1887 September (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1887 October (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1887 November (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1887 December (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1888 January - February (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1888 March - April (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1888 May - July (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1888 August (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, 1888 September (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1888 October (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, 1888 December - 1889 January (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - Miscellaneous papers, Undated (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Miscellaneous papers, Undated (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Printed material, 1844-1885, undated (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Printed material, 1853-1887, undated (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - Letter to William C. Church, 1889 August 5 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Invitation to unveiling of Ericsson Statue, Battery Park, 1893 April 26 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Iron clads of the US Navy (2/2), 1866 May (Box OS 2, Folder 8)
  - Account book, 1864 June - 1872 (Volume 1)
  - Torpedo articles: articles published, correspondents sent to, list of important papers, list of articles relating to torpedoes, 1869-1884 (Volume 2)
- Series 17. Gustavus Vasa Fox (1823-1919; bulk 1860-1889)
  The collection includes correspondence, personal papers and documents, financial records, speeches and writings, memorabilia and souvenirs, printed materials, and clippings of Gustavus Vasa Fox; correspondence of his wife Virginia Woodbury Fox; and correspondence and personal papers pertaining to other Woodbury and Fox family members.
  Gustavus Vasa Fox (1821-1883) read law with his future wife's uncle, Isaac O. Barnes, in 1837 and began his maritime career as a midshipman in 1838. He served in various naval and mercantile vessels before retiring in 1856 to manage the Bay State Woolen Mills in Lawrence, Massachusetts. His suggestions for the relief of Fort Sumter were not followed, but through connections to Abraham Lincoln via Postmaster Montgomery Blair (his wife's brother-in-law) he was appointed Assistant Secretary of the Navy under Gideon Welles in 1861. He served in that position through the Civil War, functioning as de facto chief of naval operations. He championed the cause of ironclad fighting ships, supporting John Ericsson (see Series 16) in his bid to build Monitor. Fox is credited with improving the management of the Navy that made possible its wartime victories.
  In 1866 he made the first transatlantic voyage in an ironclad (Miantonomoh) to deliver a congressional resolution to Tsar Alexander II, congratulating him on his escape from an assassination attempt. The ship made extensive stops in European ports en route. In 1867 he made an unsuccessful attempt to take over the Southwest Pacific railroad, the forerunner of the St. Louis-San Francisco railroad. In 1869 he began management of Middlesex Mills in Lowell, Massachusetts, moving to Boston in 1874 from where he commuted to Lawrence to manage Washington Mills for the commission house of Mudge, Sawyer, and Co. He retired in 1878 and pursued interests that included documenting Columbus's first landfall in the new world, and the local history and topography of New Hampshire.
  Arrangement
  The materials are arranged in 10 subseries:
  Subseries I. Correspondence
  Subseries II. Personal papers and documents
  Subseries III. Speeches and writings
  Subseries IV. Financial records
  Subseries V. Memorabilia, souvenirs, and visual materials
  Subseries VI. Printed materials and clippings
  Subseries VII. Virginia L. Woodbury Fox papers
  Subseries VIII. Woodbury and Fox family papers
  Subseries IX. Archival and filing records
  Subseries X. Bound volumes
  Each subseries is arranged chronologically unless otherwise described in its Scope and Content note. Many of the subseries were previously edited and arranged by Virginia Woodbury Fox and/or Colonel Robert Thompson in preparation for the latter's editing and publication of Fox's letters ("The Fox Papers, being the confidential correspondence of Gustavus V. Fox, Assistant Secretary of the Navy during the Civil War," Vols. I and II, edited by Colonel Robert M. Thompson and Rear Admiral Richard Wainwright and printed by DeVinne Press, New York, as the ninth and tenth volumes of the Society's publications) in 1918 and 1919. In some subseries, pages were numbered in order in pencil; in others Mrs. Fox has included notes about materials that she destroyed, erased, or otherwise redacted.
  - Subseries I. Correspondence (1838-1883)
    The correspondence includes incoming and outgoing letters, a small amount of which is personal and the bulk from Fox's tenure as Assistant Secretary of the Navy. Some of the originals were rearranged and annotated by Virginia Woodbury Fox. Her notes indicate that she destroyed those she believed to be too personal. Marie Bayless, librarian of the Naval History Society, may have typed the transcripts as part of the letters' editing by Col. Thompson. Also included are letters received by James Paulding, Assistant Secretary of the Navy before Fox. No explanation is given for their presence in the collection.
    The early letters received (1838-1860) are mostly orders to report to ships for duty, and include Fox's recommendation as a midshipman, signed by John Quincy Adams when he served as a representative from Massachusetts after his presidency. Among those in 1861 is one from Abraham Lincoln. Fox's other correspondents include John Ericsson (see Series 16) and General Ulysses S. Grant. The Civil War-era letters document routine activities of the Navy: orders, reports of activities, discussion of policy, personnel, and maneuvers. The later letters include correspondence regarding Fox's donation to St. John's Episcopal Church, Portsmouth, New Hampshire, of a credence table (to hold items required to celebrate Communion) made from the oak timbers of Admiral David Farragut's flagship Hartford.
    Some of the correspondence was arranged by month within a year and some by last name of recipient within a year. The original order has been retained.
    - Letters sent: Virginia Woodbury Fox, 1860 June 21 - 1861 October 16 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent: Virginia Woodbury Fox, 1862 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: Virginia Woodbury Fox, 1863 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: Virginia Woodbury Fox, 1864-1865 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Letters sent: Virginia Woodbury Fox, 1867-1873 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Letters sent, 1861 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent: A,B, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: C, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: D, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Letters sent: E, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Letters sent: F, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Letters sent: G, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    - Letters sent: H-K, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    - Letters sent: L, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    - Letters sent: M,O, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    - Letters sent: P,R, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    - Letters sent: S, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Letters sent: T,U,W, 1862 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Letters sent: typescripts, 1862 September - December (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Letters sent, 1863 January (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent, 1863 February (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent, 1863 March (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent, 1863 April (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Letters sent, 1863 May (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Letters sent, 1863 June (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Letters sent, 1863 July (Box 3, Folder 7)
    - Letters sent, 1863 August (Box 3, Folder 8)
    - Letters sent, 1863 September (Box 3, Folder 9)
    - Letters sent, 1863 October (Box 3, Folder 10)
    - Letters sent, 1863 November - December (Box 3, Folder 11)
    - Letters sent: B, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 12)
    - Letters sent: C-E, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 13)
    - Letters sent: F-H, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 14)
    - Letters sent: General Grant, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 15)
    - Letters sent: J-M, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 16)
    - Letters sent: O,P,R,S, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Letters sent: W, 1864 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Letters sent: A-C, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Letters sent: E-G, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Letters sent: H, J-M, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Letters sent: P,R-T,V, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Letters sent: W, 1865 (Box 4, Folder 5)
    - Letters sent, 1866-1867 (Box 4, Folder 6)
    - Letters sent, 1868 (Box 4, Folder 7)
    - Letters received, 1838-1849 (Box 4, Folder 8)
    - Letters received by James Kirk Paulding, Secretary of the Navy, 1840 - 1841 (Box 4, Folder 9)
    - Letters received, 1850 - 1860 (Box 4, Folder 10)
    - Letters received, 1861 January - April (Box 4, Folder 11)
    - Letters received, 1861 May - July (Box 4, Folder 12)
    - Letters received, 1861 August - October (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Letters received, 1861 November (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Letters received, 1861 December (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: A,B, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: C, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: D,E, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Samuel Dupont, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: John Ericsson, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: John Ericsson, typescripts, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: F, 1862 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: G, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: H-K, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: L, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: M, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: N-P, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: Porter, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: R, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: S, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: Alban Stimers, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: Alban Stimers, typescript, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: T,U, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: W, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: B-H, typescript, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: M-W, typescript, 1862 (Box 6, Folder 14)
    - Letters received: A,B, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: C, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: D, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: E, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: FA - J.M. Forbes, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: P. Forbes - Fulton, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: Gi - Gr, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: Gu, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: H, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: J-L, 1863 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: M-O, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: P, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: R, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: S, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: T,U, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: W, 1863 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: A, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: B, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: C, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: C.W. Copeland, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: D, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: E, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: J.B. Eads, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: John Ericsson, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 14)
    - Letters received: F, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 15)
    - Letters received: D.G. Farragut, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 16)
    - Letters received: J.S. Fay, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 17)
    - Letters received: J.M. Forbes, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 18)
    - Letters received: R.B. Forbes, 1864 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Letters received: G, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: F.H Gregory, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: J.W Grimes, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: H-K, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: T.A. Jenkins, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: J.W. King, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: L, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: W.K. Latimer, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: R.B. Loury, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: M, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: N,O, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: P, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: D.D. Porter, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: Q,R, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 14)
    - Letters received: S, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 15)
    - Letters received: Alban Stimers, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 16)
    - Letters received: C.K. Stribling, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 17)
    - Letters received: T, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 18)
    - Letters received: U,V, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 19)
    - Letters received: W, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 20)
    - Letters received: A. Wise, 1864 (Box 9, Folder 21)
    - Letters received: A,B, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: C, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: D, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: E, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: F, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: G, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: H-K, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: L, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: M,N, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: O, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: P, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: R, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: S, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: T, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - Letters received: U-Y, 1865 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Letters received: A, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: B, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: C-F, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: G-K, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: L-R, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: D.D. Porter, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: S-T, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Letters received: W-Y, 1866 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Letters received: B-D, 1867 (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Letters received: E-G, 1867 (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: H-R, 1867 (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Letters received: S, 1867 (Box 11, Folder 12)
    - Letters received: T-W, 1867 (Box 11, Folder 13)
    - Letters received: A-D, 1868 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Letters received: E-L, 1868 (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Letters received: M-Z, 1868 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Letters received: A-L, 1869 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Letters received: M-P, 1869 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Letters received: R, 1869 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Letters received: W-Y, 1869 (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Letters received, 1870 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Letters received, 1871 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Letters received, 1872 (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Letters received: St. John's Portsmouth - credence table donation, 1872 (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Letters received, 1873 (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Letters received, 1874 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Letters received, 1875 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Letters received, 1876 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Letters received, 1877 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Letters received, 1878 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Letters received, 1879 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Letters received, 1880 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Letters received, 1881 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Letters received, 1882 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Letters received, 1883 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Letters received, Undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Architectural plans for Montgomery Meigs residence, Washington DC, 1869 (Box OS 2, Folder 9)
  - Subseries II. Personal papers and documents (1838-1878)
    The subseries includes Fox's diaries, naval and civilian commissions and membership certificates, naval record of service, record of the sale of property, and other personal papers. His naval commissions are signed by Presidents Martin Van Buren (1838), John Tyler (1844), and Millard Fillmore (1851).
    - Diaries, 1866-1872 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Diaries, 1873-1876 June 15 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Diaries, 1876 June 16 - 1883 (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Naval commissions, 1838, 1844, 1851 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Sale of property, Lawrence, Massachusetts, to Washington Mills Co., 1854-1864 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Mt. Auburn Cemetery plot: Purchase, correspondence, 1855, 1871 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Record of service in U.S. Navy, 1866, 1888, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - U.S. tax return: draft version, 1869 (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Certificates of membership: New England Historical Society, Massachusetts Historical Society, 1875, 1876 (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Certificates of membership: New England Historic-Genealogic Society, Massachusetts Historical Society, 1875 January 6, 1883 February 8 (Box OS 2, Folder 10)
    - Commission: Justice of the Peace, Suffolk County, Massachusetts, 1878 (Box OS 1, Folder 8)
  - Subseries III. Speeches and writings (1861-1883)